A Guide to the Winslow Williams Photograph Collection, 1925-1980
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Winslow Williams Photograph Collection 1925-1980
Thomas Balch Library
VC 0003
The Winslow Williams Photograph Collection consists of approximately 12,000 negatives and 1,000 prints taken by Winslow Williams over the course of his life. Images are individually catalogued in PastPerfect, Thomas Balch Library's visual collections database available onsite, and may be identified in the online index available at www.leesburgva.gov/ThomasBalchLibrary/SpecialCollections by searching vc_0003.
Winslow Williams, Leesburg, Virginia
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Winslow Williams, Leesburg, Virginia
Alternative Form Available
Electronic media for some items
Accruals
1991.0005, 2003.0023, 2005.0109, 2005.0183
Biographical Information
Mr. Williams was born in New York in 1913, the son of a prominent lawyer. As a toddler, his family moved to Loudoun County. He learned photography from his stepmother as a child, and worked as a photographer for the Navy during World War II. After the War, he ran a photography studio in Leesburg that closed in the early 1950s. Two years before his death in 1993, he donated his collection of negatives and prints to Thomas Balch Library in Leesburg, Virginia. Mr. Williams was also the owner of the Winslow Williams Real Estate company and a founding member of the Loudoun County Board of Realtors. He was an enthusiastic naturalist who enjoyed fishing, ornithology, and gardening; for many years; his garden extended from his back yard into the rear of Thomas Balch Library.
Scope and Content
The Winslow Williams Photograph Collection consists of approximately 12,000 negatives and 1000 prints taken by Winslow Williams over the course of his life. Images are individually catalogued in PastPerfect, Thomas Balch Library's visual collections database available onsite, and may be identified in the online index available at www.leesburgva.gov/ThomasBalchLibrary/SpecialCollections by searching vc_0003.
The Collection's extensiveness, both chronologically and geographically, provides excellent documentation of daily life in Loudoun County during a key period of the county's expansion. Most of the photographs in the collection are the work product of Mr. Williams' professional photography studio and document varied facets of County life during the mid-twentieth century. Agricultural activities, sports, community, and social events are well represented. Additionally, there are many photographs of members of Loudoun County's African-American community, including the Loudoun County Emancipation Association, Douglass High School in Leesburg and Carver Elementary School in Purcellville. The collection is also very important for genealogical research; many of Williams' professional photographs are studio portraits of students and families.
Arrangement
Box
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
Loudoun Times Mirror, February 24, 1993; March 10, 1993.
Williams Family Papers (M 010), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Winslow Williams Photograph Collection (VC 0003), 1925-1980, Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Other Finding Aid
Past Perfect catalogue records
Technical Requirements
Electronic media
Related Material
Williams Family Papers (M 010)
Contents List
  - 2.5 x 3.5 prints
  - 3 x 5 prints
  - 5 x 7 prints
  - 8 x 10 prints, 0001-2999
  - 8 x 10 prints, 3000-6999
  - 8 x 10 prints, unnumbered
  - Negatives 0001 to 0449
  - Negatives 0500 to 0749
  - Negatives 0750 to 0874
  - Negatives 0875 to 0999
  - Negatives 1000 to 1149
  - Negatives 1150 to 1374
  - Negatives 1375 to 1524
  - Negatives 1525 to 1624
  - Negatives 1625 to 1719
  - Negatives 1720 to 1863
  - Negatives 1864 to 1999
  - Negatives 2000 to 2099
  - Negatives 2100 to 2309
  - Negatives 2310 to 2499
  - Negatives 2500 to 2599
  - Negatives 2600 to 2759
  - Negatives 2760 to 2859
  - Negatives 2860 to 3059
  - Negatives 3060 to 4095
  - Negatives 4096 to 4213
  - Negatives 4214 to 4299
  - Negatives 4300 to 4412
  - Negatives 4413 to 4529
  - Negatives 4530 to 4624
  - Negatives 4625 to 4739
  - Negatives 4740 to 4849
  - Negatives 4850 to 4956
  - Negatives 4957 to 5059
  - Negatives 5060 to 6049
  - Negatives 6050 to 6149
  - Negatives 6150 to 6249
  - Negatives 6250 to 6374
  - Negatives 6375 to 6519
  - Negatives 6520 to 6659
  - Negatives 6660 to 6820
  - Negatives 6824 to 6991
  - Oversized negatives
  - Oversized prints